大家好
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: Hi everyone.
我们在美丽的安特卫普Devoxx 2014现场发回报道
We're here at Devoxx 2014 in beautiful Antwerp, Belgium.
今天天气很凉爽
It's kind of cold today, actually.
我们将和我旁边的这位嘉宾谈一谈关于Chrome Apps 的相关事宜
And I'm here with my guest to talk about Chrome Apps everywhere.
请简单的做一下自我介绍吧
And maybe you can introduce yourself.
好的
ANDREW GRIEVE: Sure.
大家好  我是Andrew Grieve   目前从事Chrome移动项目
So my name's Andrew Grieve, and I work on the Chrome Apps
相关 App 的开发工作
for Mobile project.
我在 Google 从事了6年的web开发工作
Yeah, I've been doing web development for the past six
那是一段非常有趣的时光
years at Google, and it's always an exciting time.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: Yeah.
web是一个很有意思的领域
The web is an exciting place.
从事web开发工作一直都很振奋人心
And it's always a good time to be developing for the web.
言归正传  Chrome apps和mobile
So Chrome apps and mobile, so these are probably
这是我们今天将要谈论的两个话题
the two things we'll talk about.
第一个话题  Chrome apps
The first one, Chrome apps.
你能为我们或者是新的听众们  重新诠释一下
Can you maybe redefine this for those that haven't heard of it
chrome app 吗
or need a refresh.
它们和普通的网页或者是 web扩展有什么区别?
How do they differ from web pages or web extensions?
ANDREW GRIEVE: Sure.
Sure.
事实上Chrome apps的历史还算不上漫长
So Chrome apps have had-- it's actually a fairly short history.
拿我们所熟悉的桌面版chrome app来说
As we know them today for desktop,
它们在2012年稍晚的时候才正式上线  所以到现在也就两年时间
they were only made available late 2012, so only a couple years old.
Chrome apps和网页最大的区别在于
And the big difference from web pages
它们不是在浏览器的标签页里面运行的
is really that they don't run within a browser tab.
chrome apps有着独立的运行窗口
So they have to run in their own window,
这也是和广义上的web apps的一道分水岭
and this distinguishes them from regular web apps.
你可以通过Chrome web store
So you get them through the Chrome Web Store.
下载并安装它们
They are downloaded and installed.
和传统的web app不同
And the main reason why you'd want them over a regular web
chrome apps能通过相关权限  利用更加强大的API
app is that they have permission to use more powerful APIs,
比如说身份认证  socket通信
so things like the user's identity, raw sockets,
同步存储等等  更加强大引人入胜的API
or synced storage, some really more powerful and compelling APIs.
所以说  关于Chrome app你谈到了两件事
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: So there are two things you mentioned.
第一件事是它有独立的运行窗口
The first is the actual-- its own window.
那么也就意味着这是完全仿真的
It probably means it can be totally immersive
你不会知道它
and you don't really know it is powered
是由一个web引擎或者是渲染引擎所驱动的
by a web engine or a rendering engine?
是的
ANDREW GRIEVE: Right.
That's right.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: Maybe you want to comment about that.
第二件事情则是关于安全方面的
And second question is about the security aspect.
Chrome app非常的安全
It is very secure, though.
尽管它能通过更加强大API
Although it has those additional powers and APIs
来接入硬件
to access the hardware and all that,
与此同时它也非常的安全
it is very secure at the same time.
你对这两件事怎么看?
So maybe you want to comment on those two things.
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yeah.
正如你所说  Chrome apps不仅能在标签页之外运行
So as you were saying, not only do they run outside of a tab,
而且它们还有着独立于浏览器的窗口
but they run as their own window and separate from the browser.
因此也就意味着chrome apps有自己的桌面图标
So that means they have their own desktop icon,
同时也能通过Alt+tab进行程序切换
they have their own Alt tab entry.
那么对于大多数用户来说  也许他(她)们
And to most users, they'd be really hard pressed
会很难的察觉到  这一切都是源于web技术创造的
to figure out that they were built on web technology.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: Yeah.
Chrome apps本地集成于操作系统
They're very-- there's native integration
无论是任何操作的系统
with the OS, whichever OS that is.
是的
ANDREW GRIEVE: Exactly.
谈到安全  你还真说到点上了
And as far security goes, you also are right on point
总体来说
there as well, that in general, they
Chrome apps比任何一个典型的桌面程序都要安全
are more secure than typical desktop applications.
我的意思是  大部分的Chrome app
I mean, a large part of that is just because it's
都是由Chrome团队所开发的
built by the Chrome team, and I've really never
并且这是我所接触过的
been on a team more paranoid, I guess,
对安全的要求最几近于偏执的团队
about security than the Chrome team.
所有的app都运行在沙盒机制下
So all the apps run in sandboxes.
这就有效的限制了它们的能力
And there's really locked-down capabilities of what they can do.
并且内容安全策略
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: So there's a content security
也是必须要有
policy that's-- you need to have one.
不可或缺的
You can't run without one.
一个普通web站点可以没有  但是Chrome app不能
A regular website could, but a Chrome app cannot.
是的
ANDREW GRIEVE: Right.
内容安全策略是HTML5提供的新API
So content security policy is a fairly new HTML5 kind of API
来源于HTML5
that's come out in it.
目前可以广泛的在网络上进行运用
And it is available for use on the open web.
但是对于大多数网页来说这是可以选择的
But it's an opt-in thing.
然而对于Chrome apps,唯一的不同在于你别无它选
So for Chrome Apps, the difference is it's not opt-in.
你必须使用它
You must use it.
这就得以有效地防范了大多数的XSS攻击
And it really just helps prevent mostly against XSS attacks.
而理论的依据
And the rationale there is really
正因为我们给了开发者更加强悍有力的API
just because we're giving you these more capable and powerful
所以用户承担的风险比遭受攻击要高多的多
APIs, so the risk is kind of even greater to attacks.
还有一件事情
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: And part of these things,
Chrome app已经正式的上线有一段时间了
Chrome apps have been out for a little while already.
并且市面上也有许多被开发出来广受人们欢迎的
We have good examples of popular apps that have been built
优秀App
and that people are using.
但是我在想今天有没有一种新的可能
But what is new, I would think, is the ability
运用同样的技术来开发移动版的chrome apps
to build mobile apps nowadays with the same technology.
Oh  顺便说一下  chrome app就是运用web技术开发的
Oh, and by the way, Chrome apps are being built with web technologies,
我想大家都已经明白了
as I think people have understood by now.
无非是些JavaScript  HTML5以及CSS
It's all about JavaScript, HTML5, CSS.
既然现在能利用这些技术和工具能开发出类桌面程序的chrome app
So take those skills that you have, those tools that you have to build
那么理论上移动版的app也应该适用
desktop-like apps, but also mobile apps nowadays.
这其中的奥秘是什么?
So how does that work?
ANDREW GRIEVE: Right.
对这个话题我了如指掌
So that is what I'm more intimately familiar with.
这也是过去的两年  我一直在努力的方向
That's what I've been working on for the past two years.
实际上  移动版的chrome app
So Chrome Apps for Mobile is actually
目前还处于开发者预览的阶段
just still in a developer preview phase.
但是现在  我觉得还是有不少被开发出来的优秀app的
So there are some, I think, pretty compelling apps being
目前它仍然是非常之火的领域
built with it currently, but it's still hot off the press.
你可以把它看作是一个 Apache Cordova 应用
And you can mostly think of that as a Cordova application.
事实上移动版的Chrome App和普通的Apache Cordova
There's not a huge difference between a Chrome App
没有太大的区别
for Mobile application and a regular Apache Cordova application.
Apache Cordova是一个长期项目
So Apache Cordova is a fairly long-lived project,
使得开发者能够很容易的开发出基于HTML和JavaScript的应用
which makes it easy to create HTML and JavaScript
并在移动平台上部署
applications and deploy them to mobile platforms,
是一种本地应用程序  但它是用web技术开发的
as true native apps but built with web technology.
那么
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: So how
Chrome App和我开发的  比如说  一个使用WebView的
would that differ from me building, say, an Android
本地Android应用有什么不同呢
native app using a WebView?
实际本质上没什么不同
ANDREW GRIEVE: So actually it wouldn't differ all that much.
总体来说Cordova应用可以看成是
So Cordova applications, in general,
一个占据整个页面的的WebView
are a WebView taking up the entire page
并且渲染应用UI
and rendering your UI that way.
如果说最大的不同的话  那就是
So the biggest difference, I would say,
它提供了一个抽象概念  得以让你在多平台上运行
is it provides an abstraction that lets you target multiple platforms.
iOS和Android都是Chrome App所支持的
So iOS, Android is what we support
并且Cordova本身也支持跨平台的一些
on Chrome Apps for Mobile, and then Cordova itself supports
移动操作系统
pretty much every mobile operating system that you can think of.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: But do you
need to develop to some very lowest
common denominator in terms of what a WebView can support?
I know one of the nice, very new features,
I believe, in Android is the fact that the Chrome WebView is
now something that is being updated on a very regular basis.
It's been externalized.
Right
ANDREW GRIEVE: Right.
得益于Android平台上
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: You get
Chrome WebView中的WebGL支持
take benefits of having WebGL in the Chrome WebView on Android.
你大可不必在所有的平台上都那样做
You may not be able to do this on all the platforms.
那么开发者如何应对呢?
So how does a developer deal with that?
这也是项目所留下的长期的
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yes so this was historically
一个历史性的问题
a really kind of growing problem for the project for a long time.
这个问题最近才得以解决
And it's only recently kind of been addressed in a meaningful way.
我也非常高兴的的说这是一种非常讨巧的解决方法
So I'm really happy to say that there is a meaningful answer here.
随着Android L的发布
So like you said, as with Android L
系统中的WebView就是基于Chromium的
this system WebView is based on Chromium,
我相信随着chrome M37版本的来临
I believe M37 at launch, and it is updatable outside
它会作为Android的附属组件而更新的
of Android updates.
听起来棒极了
That's awesome.
对于iOS中WebView  iOS 8的诞生也带来了全新的WebView
The iOS WebView, as of iOS 8, they came up with a brand new WebView.
现在同样可以加速JavaScript以及WebGL
Now it has accelerated JavaScript and WebGL as well.
所以iOS中一样可以胜任
So very capable there.
并也iOS系统的更新  采纳率也非常之高
And iOS system updates are quite well adopted.
当然目前的问题是
Of course the question still is, what
对于那些没有使用Android L的用户来说怎么办
about people that aren't running Android L, which
has been out for approximately one day now.
我们的解决方案是利用Intel Crosswalk这个开源项目
So our answer, at least, there is the Intel Crosswalk
Intel Crosswalk是一个将Chromiium WebView
open source project, which is a bundling of the Chromium
打包进应用的Web引擎
WebView inside your application.
但其也有一定的开销  主要体现在应用体积上
So there's a couple trade-offs, mainly the size of it.
APK 文件里大约增加 17MB
It adds about 17 megabytes to your APK size.
总体来说  我们认为这也不是什么
But for most, we haven't heard that this is actually
大问题
a big problem.
至少它能让你在所有的Android版本中
And it lets you use the latest and greatest WebView
用上最新最棒的Webview
on all Android targets.
那么我们刚刚谈了一些关于
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: So walk us maybe a little bit
工作流  工具  以及API这类的东西
through the workflow, the tooling, the APIs.
假如我想开始第一个Hello world项目
I want to start my "Hello, World,"
构建属于我自己的  基于Chrome App的移动App
and probably move a little bit beyond that
那么过程应该会比刚刚谈的复杂一点儿吧
and build my first Chrome App-based mobile app.
这其中究竟是怎样实现的
What does it take?
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yeah.
有很多的方式
So there's a couple of options there.
这里说一下最简单的开发一个Hello world的方式
I'd say the easiest just for building a "Hello, World,"
使用Chrome Dev Editor就可以
and toying around a little bit is to use the Chrome Dev Editor.
Chrome Dev Editor
So this is, again, a project that
也是在今夏Google I/O上面发布的新项目
was announced at the last Google I/O this summer.
它是一个基于Chrome App构建的IDE
And it's an IDE which is actually built as a Chrome app itself.
也是一种非常酷的技术演示
So that's kind of cool as a technology demonstration.
但是该IDE只能用于创建Chrome Apps
But it's IDE just for building from Chrome Apps.
Chrome Dev Editor提供若干模板
So there's templates in there.
里面会有一个 Play 按钮
There's a Play button.
你点击按钮  它就会把你的应用
If you click Play, it'll open your application
作为桌面Chrome应用程序打开
as a desktop Chrome App.
如果你在companion tool中的下拉菜单里
And then if you use the drop-down menu in our companion
选择使为移动端提供的Chrome App开发者工具的话
tool for the Chrome App Developer tool for mobile,
就会提供一个部署到移动设备的按钮
then there's a Deploy to Mobile Device button.
所以你就可以很容易地
So you could easily, without installing any SDKs,
不用安装任何SDK就能创建面向桌面和移动设备的
play around with what your app would look like
Chrome和Web应用程序
both on mobile and on desktop.
Yeah
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: Yeah.
所以说开发一个Hello world非常之快
So the time to "Hello, World" is very
我的意思是  没有SDK
short in this-- I mean, no SDKs.
是的  这可以算得上是
ANDREW GRIEVE: That's the quickest path
写hello world最快速的捷径了
to a "Hello, World," for sure.
最后
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: And eventually, I
出色的应用已经开发完毕
do build this awesome app.
我只需要把应用打包
And I just package this and distribute this
通过Play store或者是Apple store发布就行了
through traditional Play stores or Apple stores.
对吗
Right?
就是这样的一个流程
That's how it works.
Yeah
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yeah.
Yeah.
For mobile, exactly.
So the App Store and iOS or the Play store on Android.
Once you get past your typical "Hello, World,"
you want to install our command line tools.
So we have-- Cordova's tools are based on Node.js,
as are ours, for Chrome Apps for Mobile.
And we give you kind of a Ruby on Rails style--
ALEXIS MOUSSINE POUCHKINE: Scaffolding.
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yeah, exactly.
You can do-- CCA is the name of the tool.
So cca Create Project, cca Build Android.
And that's about the extent of it,
so you need to install your SDKs at this point for this tool.
But then we give you a nice wrapper around them
to just say cca build Android, cca build iOS.
And then that's what you upload to the stores.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE POUCHKINE: And I'm
pretty sure having command line also helps with continuous integration
and integrating this in any build environment
and development environment that developers have.
Yeah
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yeah.
多数的Web开发者
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: So web developers
习惯于使用各种框架以及开发库
love using frameworks or libraries, whatever you want to call them.
对于移动的Chrome App来说,
Does Chrome Apps recommend against or to use some libraries, if any,
有任何官方推荐或者不建议使用的库或者框架吗?
especially in the mobile case?
Yeah
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yeah.
I mean, that's mostly a question we
try to stay out of a little bit.
There's new frameworks popping up all the time.
I'd say our project goal is to give you
the awesomest, most powerful blank canvas to work with as possible.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE POUCHKINE: Right.
So you're not mandating anything.
ANDREW GRIEVE: Exactly.
So Polymer, I think, is a promising project.
Angular, I've had good times with.
Ionic is a really popular Angular-based framework
for Cordova-based applications, which
works just fine for Chrome Apps for Mobile.
I mean, my personal advice is to spend the time
to at least understand what these frameworks are doing.
But I wouldn't say I have a strong preference for any of them.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE POUCHKINE: Choice is good.
I like choice.
So maybe to close off, you're here presenting at Devoxx.
And I think you also have some tips or information about what
kind of paradigm works for developers.
Maybe mobile apps.
I mean, the things that really work well,
things that don't work all that well that people shouldn't
maybe use yet or at all, because it's just
not the way they should build things in this environment.
Do you want to tell us more about this?
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yeah.
So I do have kind of developer guidance, I would say,
tips and tricks in my talk.
Mostly I'd say what works well is just--
the main thing I find is just make
sure you have that fast feedback loop when you're developing.
And that's kind of one of the best things about developing
for the web platform wherever you are.
So for Cordova applications, the main trick there
is to remember that you're building using web,
so it doesn't take much to make your mobile application
run on a desktop browser.
And Chrome Dev Tools emulation mode
gives you a really easy way to make
Chrome pretend like it's a mobile device
and shrink your view port and whatnot.
It's really fast and convenient.
So it's no replacement for testing on device,
but it certainly makes for a compelling workflow.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE POUCHKINE: Great.
So what is the status of this project altogether?
I mean, can people use it today?
And would you recommend people shipping
apps built on top of that today?
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yeah.
So I'd say every application has different requirements.
Certainly for some, this would be a perfectly reasonable
platform to use today.
There are some rough edges around us finishing up
the Crosswalk integration, for example.
For example, we haven't yet updated cca
to support the iPhone 6 Plus icon sizes.
So we'll have that done probably next week, some rough edges.
But I'd say for the most part, we're ready.
We've responded quickly to our bug tracker on GitHub.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: And this
is a good time to mention that this is a fully open source project.
ANDREW GRIEVE: Yes.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: So if people
want to support, help, or at least know what's going on,
it's done in the open.
ANDREW GRIEVE: Exactly.
Yeah.
ALEXIS MOUSSINE-POUCHKINE: OK.
Well thank you, Andrew.
That's, I guess, all the time we have for it.
So thank you for answering my questions.
And we'll be seeing you soon.
Online probably.
ANDREW GRIEVE: All right.
Thanks.